Marco Di Summa

London, SE3

Email: mdisumma@yahoo.com

Mobile: 07751841415

Website: marcodisumma.com

Recent web development graduate, currently building my experience in UX & UI design with Experience Haus' office based UX & UI Career Development Bootcamp.

My skills include graphic and web design using the Adobe Creative Suite and Figma, Front-end, Full-stack and APIs development using the JavaScript framework and the MERN stack. I am searching for an opportunity to grow my career within a creative environment.

PROJECTS

A number of project were developed during the academic studies, including:

Food Delivery Application, 2022

- Developed a full stack web application using MongoDB, Express.JS, React.JS, Node.JS.
- > Built layouts for a responsive user interface to allow visitors from any device.
- Created the company logo and the graphic assets to enhance brand recognition
- ➤ Learned ES6 features as conditional ternary operator and short short-circuit evaluation .
- > Implemented form validation, data manipulation and data retention.
- > Implemented the API endpoints supporting data type recognition and error handling.

Tower Defence Indie Game, 2021

- > Developed user interfaces with the modern javascript frameworks, HTML, and CSS3.
- > Developed the brand identity and a marketing strategy for an indie company.
- > Design graphics assets, game characters and the storytelling to enhance users engagement
- Learned image optimization, SVG graphic, for optimising web performance.
- > Applied SEO principles, user analytics, email and social media campaigns.

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022	Bachelor of Science in Web Development,	SAE Institute, London
2018 - 2020	Diploma in Graphic Design,	WAES Westminster, London
2019 - 2020	Level 2 Award in Creative Media,	WAES Westminster, London
1993 - 1998	Diploma in Fine Art & Design	Liceo Artistico Ripetta, Rome

CODING SKILLS

➤ HTML5	➤ JSON	> Node	
➤ CSS3	Javascript	MongoDb	
➤ Sass	➤ React	Python	

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite	➢ Git/GitHub	Visual Studio Code
Illustrator	InDesign	Postman
Photoshop	➤ Figma	Office Suit

ACADEMIC SKILLS

Responsive Design	➢ SEO	Media Production
Front-end Development	Analytics	Vector Graphic
Back-end development	Brand Principles	Animation
Database	Logo Creation	User research
➢ REST Api	Layout Design	> UX & UI

VOLUNTEER

2019 - 2020	Graphic Design Department	WAES Westminster, London

WORKING EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2018	Private Chef	London, UK
2014 - 2015	Cocomaya Artisan Bakery	London, UK
2012 - 2014	Tentazioni Restaurant	London, UK
1998 - 2012	Taverna Di Bacco Restaurant	Rome, Italy

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

20 years experience as a professional chef starting as owner of the family restaurant and then for a variety of establishments including Michelin starred and private clients:

- > Working under pressure and problem-solving to meet tight schedules;
- > Customer focus and attention to detail to deliver consistently high-quality service;
- > Time management and the ability to multitask in a demanding fast paced environment;
- > Leadership skills in managing kitchen staff and team dynamics;
- Creativity and adaptability in continuously evolving circumstances;
- > Understanding and implementation of budgeting and business management.

Reference upon request.